hellopretty.co.za 2018-03-11

# Privacy Policy | Hello Pretty. Buy design.

Dear Hello Pretty users who are rightly skeptical of internet safety and security,

Welcome to our Privacy Policy page. We hope you like it, because it was very expensive and drawn up by a fancy and proper lawyer. They're here to protect Hello Pretty, and to protect you also. _Someone_ has to.

 _Serious note:_ the content in the left-hand column is the Hello Pretty Privacy Policy. The right-hand column is __not__ Hello Pretty's Privacy Policy - it is purely an attempt at providing you with a concise summary of what the left hand column is saying, in non-legalese layman's terms. We can't and won't be held liable for any content in the right-hand column of this page, as it was written by laymen. So read / interpret it at your peril.

This privacy statement discloses the privacy practices for the hellopretty.co.za site. We at Hello Pretty take our users privacy seriously and we will only collect and use your personal information as outlined below and in our terms and conditions. We shall take all reasonable steps to protect your personal information.

## A. DEFINITIONS

|  |   
  
**"consent"** means any voluntary, specific and informed expression of will in terms of which a user agrees to the processing of personal information relating to him or her;

|  |   
  
**"personal information"** means information relating to an identifiable, living, natural person, and where it is applicable, an identifiable, existing juristic person, including, but not limited to—

|  |   
  
(a) information relating to the race, gender, sex, pregnancy, marital status, national, ethnic or social origin, colour, sexual orientation, age, physical or mental health, well-being, disability, religion, conscience, belief, culture, language and birth of the person;

|  |   
  
(b) information relating to the education or the medical, financial, criminal or employment history of the person;

|  |   
  
(c) any identifying number, symbol, e-mail address, physical address, telephone number or other particular assignment to the person;

|  |   
  
(d) the personal opinions, views or preferences of the person;

|  |   
  
(e) correspondence sent by the person that is implicitly or explicitly of a private or confidential nature or further correspondence that would reveal the contents of the original correspondence;

|  |   
  
(f) the views or opinions of another individual about the person; and

|  |   
  
(g) the name of the person if it appears with other personal information relating to the person or if the disclosure of the name itself would reveal information about the person; 

|  |   
  
**"seller(s)"** as defined in Hello Pretty’s terms and conditions;

|  |   
  
**"user (s)"** as defined in Hello Pretty’s terms and conditions;

|  |   
  
**1\. Personal information collected**

|  |   
  
1.1 Hello Pretty agrees to notify you of:

1.1.1 What personally identifiable information of yours or third party personal identification is collected from you via this site;

1.1.2 The organization collecting the information;

1.1.3 How the information is used;

1.1.4 With whom the information may be shared;

1.1.5 What choices are available to you regarding collection, use and distribution of the information;

1.1.6 The kind of security procedures that are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of Information under our control;

1.1.7 How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information.

|  |   
  
**2\. Collection of Personal Information**

|  |   
  
2.1. When you register an account the personal information we collect may include your:

2.1.4. Store information;

2.1.8. ID number / passport number;

2.1.9. Non-personal browsing habits and click patterns

2.1.10. Product description and images

|  |   
  
**3\. Disclosure of Personal Information**

3.1. We neither rent nor sell your Personal Information. We share such Personal Information in personally identifiable form with third parties as described below: 

3.1.1. Trusted Third Parties: We may employ other companies and people to perform tasks on our behalf and need to share your information with them to provide the Services to you. Unless we tell you differently, such third parties do not have any right to use the Personal Information we share with them beyond what is necessary to assist us. This includes third party companies and individuals employed by us to facilitate our Services, including the provision of maintenance services, database management, Web analytics and general improvement of the Services.

3.1.1.1. Hello Pretty currently uses Google Analytics as a trusted third party and may in terms of 3.1.1. use other trusted third parties in the future.

3.1.2. Business Transfers: We may choose to buy or sell assets. In these types of transactions, customer information is typically one of the business assets that is transferred. Also, if we (or substantially all of our assets) are acquired, or if we go out of business, enter bankruptcy, or go through some other change of control, Personal Information would be one of the assets transferred to or acquired by a third party.

3.1.3. Protection of Hello Pretty and Others: We reserve the right to access, read, preserve, and disclose any information that we reasonably believe is necessary to comply with law or a court order; enforce or apply our conditions of use and other agreements; or protect the rights, property, or safety of Hello Pretty, our employees, our users, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

3.1.4. With Your Consent: Except as set forth above, you will be notified when your Personal Information may be shared with third parties, and will be able to prevent the sharing of this information.

|  |   
  
**4\. How we may use your personal information**

When you register as a user on Hello Pretty’s website, we may:

4.1. use your personal information to send you marketing and/or promotional materials from time to time.

4.2. provide the seller with communication updates. Eg. Order notifications

|  |   
  
**5\. Updating Your Personal Information**

You can update your personal information anytime by accessing your account on Hello Pretty’s website.

|  |   
  
**6\. Security of Your Personal Information**

You can update your personal information anytime by accessing your account on Hello Pretty’s website.

6.1. Hello Pretty ensures that all information collected will be safely and securely stored. We protect your personal information by:

6.1.1. Restricting access to personal information

6.1.2. Maintaining technology products to prevent unauthorised computer access and security vulnerabilities 

6.1.3. Securely destroying your personal information when it's no longer needed for our record retention purposes

6.1.4. All passwords are stored using a one-way SHA-512 hashed encryption mechanism

6.1.5. Hello Pretty uses a 256 - bit SSL (secure sockets layer) encryption technology when processing your details. SSL encryption is the industry standard.

|  |   
  
**7\. Collection of Computer Data**

7.1. When you visit Hello Pretty, our company servers will automatically record information that your browser sends whenever you visit a website. This data may include: 

7.1.1. Your computer's IP address

7.1.3. Webpage you were visiting before you came to our site

7.1.4. The pages you visit on our site

7.1.5. The time spent on those pages, items and information searched for on our site, access times and dates, and other statistics

7.2. We may use your country location, as per your IP address (provided by [IP2Location](http://www.ip2location.com/)) to improve your experience on the website.

7.3. This information is collected for analysis and evaluation in order to help us improve our site and the services and products we provide.

7.4. Hello Pretty tracks personal information about users via the use of cookies. These are used to enhance your experience on the site. These cookies are stored on your computer and may be deleted by you at any time. Users may also elect to disable cookies, but we take no responsibility for a loss of functionality in this case.

|  |   
  
**8\. Amendments to the Privacy Policy.**

Hello Pretty reserves the right to modify and change the Privacy Policy at any time. Any changes to this policy will be published on our site.

|  |   
  
**9\. Complaints about breaches of privacy**

If you are not satisfied with the way in which we handle your privacy, please don't hesitate to contact us at info@hellopretty.co.za

|  |
